Jonathan Waldman

Tel Aviv, Israel 6513449 055-277-6475 • jonathanywaldman@gmail.com

Experienced security engineer who uses a background in the natural sciences to assist me in my role as a security professional. My expertise includes the highly technical and sophisticated nature of penetration testing and hacking to the administrative duties of the profession. Some current goals of mine include reverse engineering and exploit development.

EXPERIENCE

Watermark Insights, New York, NY

Senior Security Engineer
Application Security Engineer

March 2020 - Present

August 2018 - March 2020

- Conducted penetration tests against Watermark's 10 web applications and internal and external networks located in 2 distinct cloud providers and a colocation datacenter
- Enacted automated vulnerability scans using SAST/DAST tools, network agents, and host agents to cover about 80% of assets
- Conducted code reviews of .NET, Ruby, Elixir, and Java Applications
- Guided developers and DevOps engineers on remediation strategies for critical vulnerabilities
- Launched a security training program for all Watermark employees that targeted specific job functions
- Introduced company-wide initiatives on GDPR, PCI, and FERPA compliance
- Led Watermark through the SOC2 audit process and achieved certification
- Interacted with clients' risk management teams to ensure client risks are clearly addressed and mitigated
- Instituted industry best-practice auditing of software, hardware, user accounts, etc.

Cobalt.io, Remote

Core Penetration Tester

May 2019 - Present

- Conducted black-box and white-box penetration tests against a variety of web applications on small teams
- Utilized OWASP Risk Rating Methodologies to triage risks and utilized OWASP ASVS to ensure adequate test coverage

GETIDA, Secaucus, NJ

Security Engineer

October 2016 - June 2018

- Enforced security protocols necessary to prevent the exploitation (via MITM, XSS, SQL injection, brute force, session hijacking, and more) of proprietary software
- Conducted in-depth code reviews and security tests of the web app, back-end, and critical infrastructure
- Managed the migration of servers, data stores, and client systems to the cloud
- Deployed IDS and custom firewall rules thereby saving more than \$50,000/yr
- Administered secure and redundant MySQL databases responsible for storing confidential and sensitive customer information along with tens of thousands of entries per customer
- Deployed and configured a native email server tailored for custom management

Java and JavaScript Developer

October 2016 - June 2018

- Designed and implemented a unique 4-way communication protocol in Java that allows efficient and secure communication in the client-server architecture
- Coordinated the integration of the back-end server and data store with the front-end using NodeJS npm packages to provide secure communication
- Analyzed and improved the algorithms responsible for calculating legitimate and probabilistically successful claims to be submitted to FBA centers
- Built a billing and invoicing system that integrates third-party payment APIs with an internal API and the system that manages reimbursed items from FBA centers

Yeshiva University Chemistry Department, New York, NY

Research Assistant and Lab Technician

June 2015 - September 2016

- Developed a new general synthetic methodology to yield 1,8-Bis(arylamino)naphthalene molecules in 76% greater yields than previously reported and yield previously unreported molecules
- Thesis Title: Metal-Catalyzed Cross-Coupling of 1,8-Diaminonaphthalene and aryl halides

EDUCATION

Yeshiva University, Yeshiva College, New York, NY

BA, Chemistry, Jay and Jeanie Schottenstein Honors Program, GPA: 3.79
Daniel Ladell Memorial Award for Excellence in Chemistry
Dr. Samuel Soloveichik Prize for Excellence in the Study of Natural Sciences

September 2016

Computer and Network Security Self-Study

Certificates: CISSP (Associate); Offensive Security Certified Professional and Web Expert (OSCP/WE)

Websites: Damn Vulnerable Web Application (DVWA); Hackthissite.org; Codeacademy.com

Books: CISSP (ISC)2 Official Study Guide; Computer Networking: A Top-Down Approach; Java for Dummies

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Security Tools and Skill sets: Metasploit, ExploitDB, Reverse Engineering, AWS, Burp suite, Qualys, Elastic Stack, Containers, firewall configuration, IDS/IPS, ansible, PCAP, Physical network infrastructure, GCP, BigQuery Platforms: Ubuntu, Kali, Mac OS, Windows

Languages: Java, JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS, Python, bash, Elixir, C, Assembly, WordPress